<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://williamgrimes.xyz/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>williamgrimes.xyz</title><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/</link><description>my blog</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 18:31:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-21-useful-bash-commands/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-21-useful-bash-commands/</link><title>The Bourne Again Shell</title><description>A shell or command-line interpreter (CLI) provides an interface for a user to input commands in Unix-like operating systems. The shell can be used as an interactive command prompt and also written as a scripting programming language. Typically users interact with the shell using a text window called a terminal emulator, that is a computer program that emulates a video terminal. The shell maybe executing directly on the local hardware or remotely connecting to a server via Secure Shell (SSH). All Unix shells provide filename wildcarding, piping, here documents, command substitution, variables and control structures for condition-testing and iteration [1].</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-21-unix-file-system/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-21-unix-file-system/</link><title>The Unix Filesystem</title><description>The Unix operating system is a multitasking, multiuser operating system that started life under the initiative of Ken Thompson in the late 1960s at AT&amp;T Bell Labs in New Jersey, United States. Researchers at Bell Labs are also credited with developing radio astronomy, the transistor, the laser, the photovoltaic cell, the charge-coupled device (CCD), information theory, and the programming languages B, C, C++, S, SNOBOL, AWK, AMP [1]. Unix has become widely used in many computing systems, including desktop computers, servers, laptops, and mobile devices.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-07-python-tricks/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2019-09-07-python-tricks/</link><title>Python Tricks</title><description>Some Notes on Python language features, with examples... </description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2018-04-27-bitcoin-paper-companion/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2018-04-27-bitcoin-paper-companion/</link><title>Bitcoin: A Reader's Companion</title><description>Bitcoin is open-source; its design is public, nobody owns or controls Bitcoin and everyone can take part.  - bitcoin.org</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2018-04-16-nuclei-segmentation/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2018-04-16-nuclei-segmentation/</link><title>Advancing Medical Discovery through Nuclei Segmentation</title><description>Described here is an approach to the 2018 Data Science Bowl competition, this soluction  scored within the top 20% of submissions, out of over 3000 teams. The objective of the competition was to segment nuclei in cell microscopy images.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2017-08-29-fishing-risk-score/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2017-08-29-fishing-risk-score/</link><title>A Fishing Risk Framework from Satellites and Ocean Data</title><description>This proof-of-concept system assess vessels in a risk framework considering multiple factors to suggest the likelihood that a vessel has been engaging in illegal, unregulated, or unreported (IUU) fishing. The framework combines automatic identification system (AIS) tracking data with satellite imagery in construction of a risk framework. The framework combines several indicators including: the likelihood that a vessel has previously fished in a marine protected area (MPA) or exclusive economic zone (EEZ), and the intermittency of the vessel's AIS signal.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2017-04-01-text-mining-fire-incident-reports/</guid><link>http://williamgrimes.xyz/posts/2017-04-01-text-mining-fire-incident-reports/</link><title>London Fire Brigade - Topic Modelling of Incident Reports</title><description>This project used natural language processing (NLP) to analyse the London Fire Brigades corpus of free text reports. These reports are written for the most serious fire types and have been archived since the 1980s. The London Fire Brigade Business Intelligence Unit wanted to explore how to better understand and analyse these 37,000 text reports. This project shows how topic modelling can be used to understand more complex fire incidents, and explore their spatial and temporal patterns to help the London Fire Brigade in prevention of these fires. A Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) was applied using term frequency–inverse document frequency (TFIDF).</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item></channel></rss>